A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Community and Resource Development, Acting Director, Office Files of Carl Anthony FA507
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Trips, Conferences and Meetings, 2001-2005; IV (Box not specified)
  This series consists of files Mr. Anthony maintained of various conferences and meetings he attended on behalf of the Foundation. Files contain correspondence, agenda, notes, and background information for conferences held by other philanthropies such as the Land Bank Authority Forum in Flint, Michigan; conferences held with some Ford Foundation support such as the Funder’s Network Conference in New Orleans; and internal Foundation events such as the Environment and Development Affinity Group workshop in China. A few files document meetings held at the Foundation building in New York, including the Ford Foundation Community Benefits Roundtable. There are also records of Mr. Anthony’s travels for Foundation-related reasons such as his site visit to the Center for Heirs’ Property Preservation in Charleston, South Carolina.
  - Advancing Regional Equity: Second Annual Summit on Equitable Development, Social Justice and Smart Growth, Philadelphia, PA -- Agenda, Background, May 21-25, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - The African American Conversations: Black Life-New Vision -- Synopsis, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - African American Forum on Race and Regionalism, Oct 4, 2005, Detroit, MI, 2002-2005 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - African American Leadership Commission (AALC) Meeting, Chicago, IL -- Agenda, Background, Jun 15-17, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - The Center for Heirs' Property Preservation Site Visit, Charleston, SC, Oct 26-30, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Conversations on Regional Equity (CORE) Meeting, Los Angeles, CA -- Agenda, Background, Jun 5-7, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Environment and Development Affinity Group Meeting, Cape Town, South Africa -- Program, Background, Reports, Jan 21-25, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Environment and Development Affinity Group Meeting, Ooty, India -- Meeting Book, Background (1 of 2), Nov 4-9, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Environment and Development Affinity Group Meeting, Ooty, India (2 of 2), Nov 4-9, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Environment and Development Affinity Group Workshop, Shangri-La, China -- Program, Notes, Background (1 of 2), Oct 27-29, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Environment and Development Affinity Group Workshop, Shangri-La, China (2 of 2), Oct 27-29, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Ford Foundation Community Benefits Round Table -- Agenda, Presenters, Background, Notes, Jun 2, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Ford Foundation Meetings on Mixed-Income Housing and Hardest-to-House Population -- Summary, Notes, Aug 26, 2002-Jan 13, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Ford Foundation Program Division Joint Worldwide Meeting -- Rapporteur's Report, Jan 29, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Ford Foundation RED Staff Retreat -- Community and Resource Development Unit -- Notes, Handouts, Sep 29-30, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Ford Foundation and UC Santa Cruz Center for Justice, Tolerance and Community (CJTC) Meeting Re: Camden RED Learning Agenda and Applicability to New Orleans after Hurricane Katrina, Aug 11-Sep 20, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Funders Briefing on Regional Organizing, Dearborn, MI -- Agenda, Background, Dec 6-7, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Funders' Network 2002 National Conference, New Orleans, LA -- Program, Background, Mar 4-7, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Funders' Network Regional and Neighborhood Equity Gathering, Minneapolis, MN -- Agenda, Background, Apr 7-11, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Funders' Network Regional and Neighborhood Equity Project Business Meeting and Equitable Development Tour, Detroit, MI -- Agenda, Background, Jul 22-23, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Gamaliel Foundation National Leadership Assembly, Chicago, IL -- Agenda, Background, Dec 5-6, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Governor's Symposium on Smart Growth, Seaside, Fl (organized by Maryland Governor's Office) -- Conference Book with Agenda, Background, Nov 29-Dec 2, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Land Bank Authority Forum (on land use and vacant property problem), Flint, MI -- Agenda, Apr 6-8, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Living Cities Annual Meeting, Washington, DC -- Schedule, Agenda, Background, May 10-11, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Living Cities Semi-Annual Meeting, Nov 29-30, 2005, Detroit, MI -- Correspondence, Background, Agenda, July-Nov 2005 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Natural Assets in Native America -- Meeting of Practitioners of Community-Based Natural Resource Management from Native America -- Agenda, Background, Mar 13-15, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Ohio Vacant Properties Forum, Columbus, OH -- Correspondence, Agenda, Background, Oct 24-25, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Urbanization, Environment and Development Seminar, Cape Town, South Africa -- Draft Program, Notes, Feb 25-27, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Writings, 2006; V
  This series contains a book chapter titled “Race, Poverty and the Humane Metropolis: Revisiting William H. Whyte” that Mr. Anthony wrote for The Human Metropolis: People and Nature in the Twenty-First Century City edited by Rutherford H. Platt (Amherst: University of Massachusetts Press and Lincoln Institute of Land Policy, Cambridge, 2006).
  - "Race, Poverty and the Humane Metropolis: Revisiting William H. Whyte," The Human Metropolis: People and Nature in the 21st Century City (published book chapter), 2006 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Appendix A: Reports, 1998-2005
  - Buhl, Lance C., Strengthening the Community Development Partnership Strategy: Analysis and Recommendations, 1998 (Report #019631)
  - Buhl, Lance C., The Ford Foundation's Community Development Partnership Strategy: A Review, 1998 (Report #019633)
  - Bullard, Robert D.; Johnson, Glenn S.; Torres, Angel O.; Building Regional Equity into Smart Growth, 2003 (Report #019630)
  - Concordia, LLC, Camden: The Next Generation: Conditions and Opportunities for Community Development, 2004 (Report #019620)
  - Dixit, Kanak Mani, The International Year of the Mountains: Opportunities for the Ford Foundation, 2001 (Report #019625)
  - Escudero, Arthur Getz, The World Summit on Sustainable Development: Opportunities for the Ford Foundation, 2001 (Report #019626)
  - Foster, Sheila, Report to the Ford Foundation on the Camden Environmental Justice Scan, 2004 (Report #019619)
  - Hamilton, Ralph, Moving Toward Inclusion: A Proposed Approach for a Discussion of Strategy at Commonweal, 2000 (Report #019632, Report #019547)
  - Kayuni, Happy M. and Tambulasi, Richard I. C., The Key Issues in Regard to Urbanization and Environmental Change in Malawi, 2005 (Report #019634)
  - La Vina, Antonio, From Kyoto to Marrakech: Global Climate Politics and Local Communities, 2002 (Report #019627)
  - La Vina, Antonio, Summary Report: The World Summit on Sustainable Development and International Year on Ecotourism and Mountains, 2001 (Report #019624)
  - La Vina, Antonio, The Emerging Global Regime on Access and Benefit Sharing for Genetic Resources: Implications for Local Communities, 2002 (Report #019628)
  - La Vina, Antonio, The International Year of Ecotourism: Opportunities for the Ford Foundation, 2001 (Report #019623)
  - Mabala, Richard, From Prevention to Protection for AIDS: Addressing Vulnerability in Urban Areas, 2005 (Report #019640)
  - Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation, The Reinvestment Fund, The Camden Project: A Framework for Investment, 2003 (Report #019621)
  - Mitlin, Diana, Inter-Dependency and Synergy in Poverty Reduction, 2005 (Report #019641)
  - Nkhoma, Sikhulile, Malawi Homeless People's Federation, 2005 (Report #019636)
  - Nowak, Jeremy, Spatial Targeting Strategies: Reflections from Camden, 2003 (Report #019617)
  - Pavel, M. Paloma, Executive Summary: Strategic Communications Practices at the Ford Foundation, 2003 (Report #019614)
  - Pavel, M. Paloma, Strategic Communications Plan, 2003 (Report #019616)
  - Pavel, M. Paloma, Vision to Action: A Strategic Communications Plan for the SMCI 2004-2006: Executive Summary (Report #019615)
  - Sabry, Sarah, The Social Aid and Assistance Programme of the Government of Egypt - A Critical Review, 2005 (Report #019638)
  - Swilling, Mark, Sustainability and Infrastructure Planning in South Africa: A Cape Town Case Study, 2005 (Report #019635)
  - Tacoli, Cecilia, Rural-Urban Linkages in Africa: Their Role in Livelihood Transformations and Poverty Reduction, 2005 (Report #019637)
  - The Reinvestment Fund, Developing a Camden Strategy: A partnership with the Ford Foundation: A Concept Paper, 2002 (Report #019618)
  - The Reinvestment Fund, The Camden Project: Notes for the Regional Equity Demonstration, undated (Report #019622)
  - Van Donk, Mirjam, "Positive" Urban Futures in Sub-Saharan Africa: HIV/AIDS, 2005 (Report #019639)
  - Weiss, Jonathan D., The Engineering/Construction Industry and Sustainable Metropolitan Communities, 2003 (Report #019629)